Morris Kyalo

P.O. Box 1996 - 90100, Machakos Tel: +254-799799828

Email: mauricekyallo@gmail.com Portfolio: https://morriskyalo.github.io

PERSONAL DETAILS

• Date of Birth: 1st September 1999

Nationality KenyanGender Male

ID No. 36760699Marital Status Single

EDUCATION

Diploma in Information and Communication Technology (KNEC)

Christian

Sep 2017 - Jan 2021

Machakos Institute of Technology

• Graduated with, Upper Credit

Computer Packages

Religion

March - May 2017

Machakos Institute of Technology

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

2013 - 2016

Kabaa High School

Mean grade attained, C

CAREER PROFILE

A confident and highly skilled graduate with a Diploma in Information and Communication Technology; 1+ years experience in the ICT department, installing and maintaining networks and data entry to the organization's websites. Demonstrated knowledge and experience in designing, installing operating, and information technology infrastructure. Additional skills in tutoring, research, graphics design, and forex trading in addition to technical expertise

Proven record of success in diagnosing and resolving technical/officers' inquiries. Able to clearly understand problems and find positive solutions through the use of troubleshooting critical thinking problem-solving teamwork and communication

PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

- High integrity, dependability, and confidentiality
- Adaptability, flexibility, and self-driven
- Innovative, results-oriented, and efficient planner
- Accuracy and attention to details
- Strong interpersonal skills to enhance teamwork
- Ability to work within tight timelines and deliver excellent outcomes

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Website, Apps, UI/UX, and Database Design & Development
- Knowledge in Operating Systems Architectures (Windows, Mac, Linux)
- CCNA Curriculum Material
- Network Management (IP addressing, Switching & Routing)
- Systems Analysis & Requirement gathering
- Programming (C++, PHP, .Net)
- **Basics of Digital Transmissions**
- Basics of Artificial Intelligence and Office automation frameworks

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

New Birth Institute of Professional Studies

Feb 2022 to date

Designation: Part-time ICT Tutor

Tutoring DICT Module II students through 6 Units tested by the KNEC

Machakos County Government (PSQM & ICT)

Feb 2021 to date

Designation: Intern

Installing Operating Systems, configuring network devices to the organization's IP addressing server, data entry to the organization's websites, troubleshooting inefficiencies from officers' PCs, maintaining seamless servers, systems, and office workflow, securing office PCs with anti-viruses, drafting policies and real-time communication on the recommended software and hardware upgrades

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- Coding and development
- Networking
- Building DIY computer hardware systems
- Playing Lawn tennis

REFEREES

Please feel free to contact the under mentioned concerning my abilities, competencies, and work ethics;

Daniel Kivuitu Mwalali
Systems Analyst
Marchaltas Caunty Cayaranan

Machakos County Government P.O. Box 1996-9010 Machakos

Phillip Biego Deputy Principal

Cell: **0754780447**

Machakos Institute of Technology

P.O Box 2069-90100, Machakos

Cell: 0733320540